SAMEE UR REHMAN

React-Js Developer, HTML, CSS, PHP, Jira, C++, PostgreSQL, Node, Express, GraphQl, Integrating Web Applications with RESTAPI's, Communication, Leadership, Management.

DESCRIPTION

I am a dedicated React JS Developer with a focus on creating outstanding web applications with a Handsome Experience of **More than 1** year of Experience in React JS Development for a variety of organizations across world.

My experiences include *Leading Teams* and building systems from the ground up. It includes working on all aspects of Web Application Development ranging from *UI*, *API's Integration* and, architecture design for a new, or existing website.

I have Experience in,

- Designing and implementing core framework components and reusable libraries.
- Ability to handle multiple tasks and solve complex problems.
- Involved in Strong technical documentations.
- An integrative team player with excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

EXPERIENCE

Codistan Ventures, Islamabad, Pakistan — Frontend Developer 2 Nov 2023 — PRESENT Software, IT Company

Lancer Hut, Islamabad, Pakistan — *Junior Frontend Developer*11 July 2022 – 25 July 2023
Software, IT Company

Bikter Tech, Islamabad, Pakistan — *Frontend Intern* 11 April 2022, - 11 June 2022 Software, IT Industry

EDUCATION

Capital University of Science and Technology (CUST), Islamabad, Pakistan

— BS SOFTWARE ENGINEERING (2017 - 2022)

Email: SAMEE6812@gmail.com

Phone: +92-306-5145627

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samee6812/

GitHub

https://github.com/sameerehman001

SKILLS

React.js, Next.js, C++, Java, OOP
Understanding of REST API's, GraphQI.
UI and Back-End Integration through API's.Strong
Understanding of JavaScript & TypeScript.
Strong understanding of HTML, CSS, & MUI.
Strong Understanding of Bootstrap, Tailwind,
MUI.

Leadership, Project Management.

Academic Projects

- → Auto Car Work Shop System PHP and SQL.
- → LMS in HTML, CSS, PHP.
- → Line Following Car in IOT.

Industrial Projects

- → Ranchers Cafe Web_App & Delivery_App in TypeScript & NextJS. (https://rancherscafe.com/)
- → Predictive Analysis in React-Js, GraphQL,
- → Campsite Admin-panel in React-Js, Rest-API's
- → ZeemDev Admin-panel_in React-Js (https://harvestfundmanagement.com/admi n-panel)
- → Video-Overlay Admin-_ panel in React-js, Rest-API's.
- → My Portfolio website in Next.js and TailwindCSS (https://portfoliowebsitefinal.netlify.app/)